# **Pratik Var**

# Front-End Developer

Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn

#### **Pratik Var**

315, Zolo Republic, DLF Phase 3 Gurgaon, HR 122002 India

(+91) 9205122400 pratikvar@pm.me

#### **Skills**

I am a design-oriented front-end developer proficient in HTML, CSS, JS and specializing in React. I have experience in building responsive UIs, following the W3C standards and mobile-first design; and I'm well-versed with the common best practices for accessibility and SEO. I've also worked with front-end libraries and frameworks like Bootstrap, Gatsby, Sass, Tailwind CSS, Material-UI, D3, and a few back-end technologies like Firebase, Node.js, and GraphQL. I'm a problem-solver at heart and a quick learner, and I strive in a challenging work environment.

### Languages

Hindi - Native English - Bilingual

German - Conversational

## **Experience**

Front-End Intern | REVOS Auto Tech (an EV startup)

NOV 2020 - PRESENT

Freelance Developer | Upwork

JAN 2021 - FEB 2021

My personal website and portfolio: pratvar.com

#### **Education**

**Universität des Saarlandes** | BSc plus MINT (German for "STEM")

2021, SAARBRÜCKEN, GERMANY

Deferred due to COVID-19

#### **freeCodeCamp** | Front-End Development

APR 2020 - SEP 2020, ONLINE

Responsive Web Design | JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures | Front End Libraries

Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee | Data Science Specialization

JUN 2020 - PRESENT, ONLINE

**Language Pantheon** | German (Level B1)

SEP 2019 - MAR 2020, NEW DELHI

Alwar Public School | High School Diploma (CBSE, India)

2015 - 2019, RAJASTHAN